<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>admin &#8211; Larong Tabletop</title>
	<atom:link href="./index.html" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>./../../../../index.html</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>
	Sun, 09 Jun 2019 14:01:23 +0000	</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.1.1</generator>

<image>
	<url>./../../../../wp-content/uploads/2019/03/Asset-3-65x65.png</url>
	<title>admin &#8211; Larong Tabletop</title>
	<link>./../../../../index.html</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Tidbits of Tadhana</title>
		<link>./../../../2018/11/19/tidbits-of-tadhana/index.html?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=tidbits-of-tadhana</link>
				<comments>./../../../2018/11/19/tidbits-of-tadhana/index.html#respond</comments>
				<pubDate>Mon, 19 Nov 2018 15:26:06 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Stories]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">./../../../../index.html?p=4656</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[Tadhana: The Game Itself   So this is Tadhana, a fantasy-adventure tabletop rpg that has similarities with other rpgs like Dungeons and Dragons, and Call of Cthulu. It uses a similar number-stat based gameplay mechanic that heavily impacts the character/avatar you’re playing as and of course like all campaigns it has an end goal and [&#8230;]]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>Tadhana: The Game Itself</strong></p>
<p><strong> </strong></p>
<p>So this is Tadhana, a fantasy-adventure tabletop rpg that has similarities with other rpgs like Dungeons and Dragons, and Call of Cthulu. It uses a similar number-stat based gameplay mechanic that heavily impacts the character/avatar you’re playing as and of course like all campaigns it has an end goal and that it’s up to your own decisions on how you want to reach the end goal. A unique aspect to the Tadhana rpg is that it actually uses cards instead of dice, making it give off a more “fantasy-magic” feel to the game. It just feels like using Tarot Cards to decide your fate which is pretty neat and in my opinion a concept that hasn’t been used much in other tabletop rpgs.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Now that we’ve covered a general idea of what Tadhana is let’s move on to the world itself, like I said it’s a fantasy-adventure so in which case everything is mythical and magic. Beings like elves, horses, dead people, half dead people, and don’t forget regular normal people for players who feel like they wanna start out with a basic class without any drawbacks early on in the game. It’s not like they’re gonna abuse the fact that there might be certain exploits in the game because there aren’t any (pls dont look it up just enjoy the game i beg you pls im being held captive against my will) Oh, I also forgot to mention that the game’s world is set in a Philippine Mythological setting, which explains a lot of why the races are all from Philippine Mythology, and the classes as well, making the whole setting with some accentuated tribal inspired cultures for its inhabitants or NPCs and Avatars/Players alike.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>Tadhana: Character Creation</strong></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>To start, since Tadhana has a unique was of “rolling dice” or rather using cards to determine actions and whatnot your character can do in the game. It’s also used as getting starting stats per skills your character uses which are Laban, Husay, Talisik, and Diwa. Later on, creating your character is fairly standard as with all tabletop rpgs: choosing a class, a race, and an occupation. All in all, pretty standard stuff. Also with adding powers/magic are pretty standard as you’re designated with what kind of powers you need to be starting. There’s a step-by-step guide in the starter core guidebook so I won’t need to explain but basically to give the rundown: If your character is able to create that power/magic, feel free to do so and also add some custom effects if possible.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Going back to skills there are the four main ones that are being heavily used in this game which are Laban, Husay, Talisik, and Diwa. They basically replace the main six skills in DnD which are Strength, Constitution, Charisma, Intelligence, Wisdom, and Dexterity. There are also the subskills like persuasion and whatnot but the system in Tadhana mainly uses the four skills already as the rest. What each skills do are pretty self explanatory in the guidebook so I suggest checking it out. The professions are also something to take note of, they count as your current occupation in the game and by default you start with one and later on can add more depending on which NPC you’ll talk to to get a new profession. Lastly the starting equipment, right off the bat you get to choose pretty much anything from a list in the guidebook, there isn’t much of a currency system if you want to buy or sell items to vendors but more or less they’re kinda just starting equipment plus depending on the Overseer or rather Dungeon Master he/she will rewards players anyway so there really isn’t much explaining about that part.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>Tadhana: The Backstory</strong></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>This is more of a continuation from <strong>Character Creation</strong> but basically, Tadhana has a system called Destiny System, it’s more or less a background for your character to fit in nicely with the whole narrative of the story. Feel free to choose pretty much anything you’d like your character to have, keep in mind that it also helps DMs or Overseers with the overall narrative standpoint while world building as they may come up with certain ideas, adventures, and maybe a fun addition to the campaigns as you see your character be engulfed in the narrative that you yourself have created beforehand.</p>
<p>&#8211; <em>Jason Cabili</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>./../../../2018/11/19/tidbits-of-tadhana/feed/index.html</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
							</item>
		<item>
		<title>Tadhana and RPG</title>
		<link>./../../../2018/11/19/tadhana-and-rpg/index.html?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=tadhana-and-rpg</link>
				<comments>./../../../2018/11/19/tadhana-and-rpg/index.html#respond</comments>
				<pubDate>Mon, 19 Nov 2018 15:22:22 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Stories]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">./../../../../index.html?p=4654</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[Tabletop role playing games (RPG) aren’t all that different once you strip them down to their core. There would be a dungeon master (referred to as the DM), and the players running a scenario in which the DM would narrate the adventure while the players run through it with their own created characters with a [&#8230;]]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Tabletop role playing games (RPG) aren’t all that different once you strip them down to their core. There would be a dungeon master (referred to as the DM), and the players running a scenario in which the DM would narrate the adventure while the players run through it with their own created characters with a set of stats and abilities their characters have and roll dice for their actions. Famous role playing games all follow these essentials like Dungeons &amp; Dragons, Pathfinder, and Fate. Some would even call these essentials as what makes a role playing game a role playing game. Tadhana is no different in this regard.</p>
<p>Tadhana is much more simpler than something like Dungeons &amp; Dragons (D&amp;D) in that there are a small number of stats compared to the multitudes of stats you need to keep track of in D&amp;D. The big difference between Tadhana and other RPGs is that Tadhana has these deck of cards called the Destiny Deck. These deck of cards replaces dice rolls for random encounters. These cards are used to ‘roll’ various results in accomplishing what a player wants to do. Although in Tadhana there is no such thing as an EXP point system for gaining levels, instead they simplified it into a milestone system in order to keep the pace of the game without slowing down. This way of leveling up is a very smooth experience since the players don’t need to keep track of the EXP values. As a DM, Tadhana has an easier way to track this down and make it easier for the players and for the DM to calculate how every player can gain experience without slowing down the game. Combat works the same way as other RPGs except in Tadhana there is a ‘Talk Phase’ in which players can interact before any combat actions can be done which is different from other RPGs. Terrain around the battlefield can be used as cover whether full or partial cover and that can affect the way the battle flows as stats can change depending on the state of defense of the characters. Interaction outside combat lies in the DM narrating the story usually with a grand campaign with a quest that the players can work on. In Tadhana, reputations and relationships also play a role in the story in which the players can tame animals and socialize with non playable characters (NPCs). There is also no currency in Tadhana unlike in other RPGs and so the main form of getting items is Trading which fits in with the theme of the game.</p>
<p>RPGs are unique due to their different themes and characters that they can use but at their core they are the same with a few slight differences. Tadhana tries to change it up a bit by adding in the Trials of Fate cards that replace dice rolls and various things that spice up the combat and make things simpler for the players to play like a milestone system and less stats and attributes to keep track of, this makes Tadhana easy to teach to newcomers and easier for them to get the hang of RPGs compared to other more complicated systems. The theme is nice and interesting which should make it easier to lull in players into the world and have them playing in no time.</p>
<p>&#8211; <em>Sam See</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>./../../../2018/11/19/tadhana-and-rpg/feed/index.html</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
							</item>
		<item>
		<title>Thoughts on Darna and Talinghaga</title>
		<link>./../../../2018/11/14/thoughts-on-darna-and-talinghaga/index.html?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=thoughts-on-darna-and-talinghaga</link>
				<comments>./../../../2018/11/14/thoughts-on-darna-and-talinghaga/index.html#respond</comments>
				<pubDate>Wed, 14 Nov 2018 15:10:25 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Stories]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">./../../../../index.html?p=2285</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[Talinghaga Talinghaga is a Filipino board game which can be described as Filipino Scrabble. The game consists of cards containing syllables/letters from the Filipino alphabet with their corresponding, written in both phonetic and alibata. The game’s rules were easy enough to understand as well as the point system. It’s a fun board game to play, [&#8230;]]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong><u>Talinghaga</u></strong></p>
<p>Talinghaga is a Filipino board game which can be described as Filipino Scrabble. The game consists of cards containing syllables/letters from the Filipino alphabet with their corresponding, written in both phonetic and alibata. The game’s rules were easy enough to understand as well as the point system. It’s a fun board game to play, and I think it is a good exercise and test to see how well you know the Filipino language. One of the interesting features of the game is how you can steal an opponent’s created word and make it into a much longer word to claim your own. I hope this game gets developed more for mass production, as it is a great way for teaching someone the Filipino language as well. Its suitable for learning children to adults who barely use the language. You can play it with your friends who know Filipino very well and have a battle of who knows more words or with your friends who don’t know how to speak it very well and make fun of them, teaching them in the process. It’s a fun game for everyone.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong><u>Darna Card Game</u></strong></p>
<p>The game’s rules are simple, shuffled bato cards would be given to you, not knowing if what you get is THE bato or not. Along with the bato card, you get to discard cards that would either help or hinder you into winning. The goal is for you to get the crystal bato card, and if you THINK or if you are sure you have it, you shout “DARNA”. If you do have it, you win and if you don’t you’re out. It’s a fun game to play with friends and also a unique and challenging strategy game. It can also be quite thrilling as you’re not sure who has the actual bato, and also hilarious to see which one shouts darna. One of the things that appealed to me was the art on the cards. It was interesting and fun, as each card has a character and corresponding move.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><em>Gabrielle Dimalanta</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>./../../../2018/11/14/thoughts-on-darna-and-talinghaga/feed/index.html</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
							</item>
		<item>
		<title>My Experience with Talinghaga and Tala</title>
		<link>./../../../2018/11/14/my-experience-with-talinghaga-and-tala/index.html?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=my-experience-with-talinghaga-and-tala</link>
				<comments>./../../../2018/11/14/my-experience-with-talinghaga-and-tala/index.html#respond</comments>
				<pubDate>Wed, 14 Nov 2018 15:09:18 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Stories]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">./../../../../index.html?p=2282</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[After hearing about the game Talinghaga from my friends, I thought to myself, “Yep, I’ll definitely lose in the first round”. The game was supposed to help people who are bad in Filipino and it was made for people who are bad at Filipino. Certainly, the perfect game for me. When I started playing the [&#8230;]]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>After hearing about the game Talinghaga from my friends, I thought to myself, “Yep, I’ll definitely lose in the first round”. The game was supposed to help people who are bad in Filipino and it was made for people who are bad at Filipino. Certainly, the perfect game for me. When I started playing the game, it looked like a Filipino version of Scrabble, minus the board and letter pieces but replaced with cards. The game was not easy to understand at first for me, but give or take 5 minutes into the game, I managed to understand what’s going on and ended up liking the game. The mechanics of the game were certainly well thought of and the cards were very well designed. The game also implemented the use of Baybayin very well and certainly made it a little harder for Non-Filipino speaking people to come up with words. Over-all the game is certainly very different from scrabble, and they hit the objective to it being a game for “People who have difficulties speaking and understanding Filipino”. If more people play this game at school or with family, we would be able to have a better appreciation for the Filipino language and the writing style of Baybayin.</p>
<p>Another game that we played was “Tala”, which to my surprised was only for two people. Apparently in the game, we had to set up four tiles and with the star cards that we had, we would have to form a pattern on those tiles based on one of the cards we had. If we managed to form the pattern, we take the tiles and discard the star pattern we used and get another card and place down another tile. First to get three tiles wins in the end. The instructions were very simple, but the process of playing was very difficult. And by difficult, I mean I’m the type of person who does not like to think, and this game certainly made me think very hard on the pattern that I should be making. I would always check my cards and then back at the tiles and think. While I was playing the game, I certainly got a small headache from what to do next. In the end, I managed to win with the surprising help of my opponent. Over all, the game was very well thought off and the mechanics are very simple and easy to understand. Playing the game was not good for my head but it is worth playing if you are the type of person who loves to think and strategies.</p>
<p>Over all, the two games were not that difficult to understand as you progress through it. At the start, yes, it will be confusing because you’ve only just started playing but going through the gaming process was certainly fun. It is great to see that Filipinos have started developing their own brand of board games, especially board games that implement a little bit of Filipino culture such as language. The game Talinghaga was certainly reminiscent of Scrabble, but it gave its own twist by using the Philippines language of Baybayin, which gave it some originality. The game, Tala, sort of reminds me of tick-tac-toe and another game I’ve played before, but it had different assets implemented to it to make it its own original game. It’s amazing to see what the Filipino mind can create, with the help of our own culture.</p>
<p>In the end, I hope that I will be able to see these games flourish within the board gaming community, as it slowly ranks up to the level of being a well-known board game for friends and families to play with, and possibly even play it in school, to be used as an educational activity for students, especially Talinghaga to those who cannot speak Filipino. It is truly a blessing that Filipinos can come up with something such as this.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><em>Paula Capanas</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>./../../../2018/11/14/my-experience-with-talinghaga-and-tala/feed/index.html</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
							</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
